Ensar MAKAS

Software Developer

Sarıyer, İstanbul

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ensar-makas/ https://github.com/rasnesakam ensar.makas@gmail.com https://emakas.net/ +90 539 340 8356

ABOUT

As a computer engineering graduate, I have built a solid foundation in software development with a particular focus on backend technologies. I have worked on projects involving API design, authentication, and system architecture. My hands-on education at Ecole 42 Istanbul has strengthened my problem-solving and collaborative coding skills.

SKILLS

- Java, C#, Javascript, Typescript PostgreSQL, MSSQL, MySQL
- Spring Boot Framework
- NET Core Framework
- Hibernate Orm, EF Core
- Git Version Controlling
- Linux / Unix Systems
- Bash Shell Commands
- Docker Containerization

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Veripark March 2024 - Present

Software Developer

Developed and implemented a CRM solutions for clients and integrated their datas into our CRM system in real time using Dynamics CRM 365. Developed SOAP services as a proxy service to integrate rest or soap services of clients into our system.

Tech Stack:

- .NET WCF
- SOAP Services
- Typescript
- MSSQL

Koc Sistem Sep 2022 - Dec 2022

Software Developer Intern

Developed E-Commerce API that handles orders and products. Implemented authorization using JWT tokens. Also implemented Mediator design pattern in our multi-layer arhitecture.

Tech Stack:

- .NET Core
- EF Core for ORM, Fluent API for mappings
- Jwt Token based authentication
- Swagger for documentation
- Mediator Design Pattern and Multi Layer Architecture as project architecture

Aug 2020 - May 2022 Kando Bilisim

Software Developer Intern

Developed small CRM system with PHP, Javascript, HTML and CSS. Built a real estate gallery site for client

Tech Stack

- .NET Core MVC.
- PHP, Js, HTML, CSS

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Computer Engineering

Majors: Computer Engineering **Beykent University**

Ecole 42 Istanbul

Majors: Computer Science Fcole 42

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Computer Society Chairman

IEEE Beykent Student Club

Community Volunteer

IEEE Beykent Student Club

PROJECT EXPERIENCES

Users API (Identity-Authentication Module)

https://github.com/rasnesakam/emakas-users

Users API is an Identity-Authentication module that handles users that works in same organizations. Users are grouped by teams. Because of this project handles authentication and authorization operations. This module places as base module in microservice ecosystem. Handles authentication and authorization operations by Jwt tokens and given permissions to users, teams and registered applications for registered resources

Tech Stack:

- · Spring Boot, Spring Security
- MapStruct as mapper class
- Lombok to simplify POJO Objects
- PostgreSQL as database
- · React Js as UI development
- React-Router-DOM as page navigation
- · Vite for building UI
- Docker as Containerization

Trascendence Nov 2023 - Mar 2024

https://github.com/rasnesakam/Trascendence

Designed and developed a gaming application using Django, facilitating communication between the backend and frontend through REST principles. This project supports messaging between users over the TCP protocol and WebSockets, along with one-on-one or tournament-style gameplay, and friend requests. User actions are notified, excluding blocking notifications, and game data is stored in a PostgreSQL database. The frontend and backend are implemented as separate microservices, with their connection managed through Docker. Developed as 42 project

Tech Stack:

- · Django as Backend
- Django Channel for establishing websockets
- PostgreSQL as database
- Pure Js, HTML, CSS as UI development
- · Nginx as gateway
- Docker as Containerization

Internet Relay Chat Jun 2023 - Aug 2024

https://github.com/rasnesakam/internet-relay-chat

Internet Relay Chat is an implementation of IRC protocol that written in C++ 1998 standards. IRC is where people can chat with each other via groups or one to one. Developed as 42 project

Tech Stack:

- C++ 98 as language
- System level sockets
- Makefile to build binaries

Depln Apr 2024 - Jun 2021

https://github.com/rasnesakam/DepIn

Depln is a dependency Injection tool that written in java. Scans class structures by JSON configuration files and instantiates classes automatically.

Tech Stack:

- Java 17 as language
- Reflect API to replicate classes
- · JUnit for testing

emakas-blog Mar 2023 - Present

https://github.com/rasnesakam/emakas-blogs

IBlog API is a microservice that stores and publishes blog posts of users. It utilizes Node Js with Typescript. For listenning HTTP requests, It uses Express Js as web framework. Db entities are mapped via Prisma Orm

Tech Stack:

- Typescript as language
- Node Js as build and running environment
- Express Js for Web Framework
- Prisma Orm for Orm solution

10V 2023 - IVIAI

Oct 2022 - Present